Guide to the Irving Rosenthal Papers
Department of Special Collections
Irving Rosenthal papers
ca. 1950-1996
M1550
Rosenthal, Irving, 1930-
ca. 23 linear ft. (32 manuscript boxes, 1 half box, 7 flat boxes, 1 tube)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The papers document Irving Rosenthal's life from his childhood onwards, containing outgoing correspondence, doctoral dissertation materials, manuscript materials, and detailed documentation of his own novel, Sheeper. There are materials relating to his editorship of The Chicago Review and Big Table, his trip to Cuba in 1961, and his life in Tangier from 1962-1964. Also included are manuscripts by, and correspondence with, William Burroughs, Edward Dahlberg, Herbert Huncke, Allen Ginsberg, and Jack Smith. Other significant figures featured in the collection include Paul Bowles, Paul Carroll, Gregory Corso, Elsa Dorfman, Lawrence Ferlinghetti, George Harris III, Jack Kerouac, Eila Kokkinen, Robert LaVigne, Phillip Lamantia, Edward Marshall, Michael McClure, Peter Orlovsky, Ed Sanders, Philip Whalen, and John Wieners.
Access
Collection is open for research, except half box 40, which is closed until 01/01/2014; materials must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in December 2006. Accession 2005-126
Biography / Administrative History
Irving Rosenthal was born in San Francisco on October 9, 1930. He attended Pomona College and then the University of Chicago, where he did graduate work in human development.
In the late 1950s, Rosenthal became editor of The Chicago Review and succeeded in publishing poetry by Jack Kerouac, prose by Edward Dahlberg, and the first parts of William Burroughs's Naked Lunch before the University of Chicago censored his editorial practice. After resigning from The Chicago Review, he moved to New York and started Big Table magazine with the help of a colleague. Its first issue included the entire contents of the suppressed 1959 winter edition of The Chicago Review. Although Big Table survived only briefly, its few issues strengthened Rosenthal's connection to both the Dahlberg circle and the Beats.
Living in New York, Rosenthal developed particularly close relationships with Allen Ginsberg, Hubert Huncke, and other figures in the Beat movement. He subsequently visited Burroughs and Paul Bowles in Tangier and lived there from 1962 to1964. During this period he also began work on a novel, Sheeper, which was later published by Grove Press in 1967. Returning to New York, Rosenthal was drawn into the orbit of the experimental film maker, Jack Smith, and appeared in Flaming Creatures and No President.
In 1967 Rosenthal moved back to San Francisco with George Harris, founder of the Cockettes, to start the Kaliflower commune, which continues to exist and where he still lives.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, typescripts, photographs, artwork, periodicals, and ephemera. Folder numbers consist of the "box number.folder number," e.g. "1.12."
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in FOUR series:
Series I. Personal
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Miscellaneous correspondence
Series IV. Professional
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
American literature- -20th century.; Beat generation.; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-; Bassin, Barry.; Birnbaum, Peter.; Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Bremser, Bonnie, 1939-; Bremser, Ray.; Brown, Geoffrey.; Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997.; Carroll, Paul, 1927-; Cohen, Ira.; Corso, Gregory.; Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-1977.; Dorfman, Elsa.; Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.; Fisher, Melvin.; Fles, John.; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997.; Gurin, David.; Harris, George.; Hasselwood, Dave.; Heine, William.; Huncke, Herbert.; Kerouac, Jack, 1922-1969.; Kokkinen, Eila.; LaVigne, Robert, 1928-; Lamantia, Philip, 1927-2005.; Marshall, Edward.; McClure, Michael.; Orlovsky, Peter, 1933-; Podell, Albert.; Rechy, John.; Rogers, Carl R. (Carl Ransom), 1902-1987.; Romagnolo, Fred.; Rosenthal, Irving, 1930-; Sanders, Ed.; Sanders, Melvin.; Schleifer, Marc.; Skir, Leo.; Smith, Jack, 1932-1989; Standal, Stanley W., 1922-; Sturz, Herbert.; Usdansky, George, 1924-; Whalen, Philip.; Wieners, John, 1934-; Zazeela, Marian.; Kerouac, Jack, 1922-1969. Old Angel Midnight; Burroughs, William S., 1914-1997. Naked lunch; Huncke, Herbert. Huncke's journal; Rosenthal, Irving, 1930- Sheeper; "the poet! the crooked! the extra-fingered!"; Chicago review.; Big table.
Other Finding Aids
Gregory Corso Papers, M0721
Allen Ginsberg Papers, M0733
Container List
- Series I. PERSONAL
  This series contains materials from Rosenthal's childhood, college years, early jobs, personal interests, and travels.
  - Agnews State Hospital, 1951: materials from summer job at Agnews State Hospital; includes an evaluation of his experience., 1.1.
  - Athens, Greece, 1964: materials from stay; includes letters, tickets, business cards, receipts, notes, and map., 1.2.
  - Autobiographical statements and resumes, 1952-1965, 1.3.
  - Bankbooks, 1948-1967, 1.4.
  - Beads, 1963: correspondence with bead sellers regarding business Rosenthal tried to start in Tangier, Morocco; includes photographs., 1.5.
  - Camp Ramapo, 1955: materials relating to Rosenthal's summer job at Camp Ramapo; includes descriptions of the camp, schedules, notes, photographs of Rosenthal, and negatives., 1.6.
  - Childhood, 1932-1948: materials from childhood and high-school years; includes stamp albums, programs, report cards, and high-school diploma., 1.7.
  - Childhood, ca. 1932-1935: photographs of Rosenthal and family; removed from folder # 1.7., 1.8.
  - Childhood, autograph collection, 1945: autographs and autograph book, 1.9.
  - Childhood, senior yearbook, 1948, 1.10.
  - College years, 1948-1952, 1.11-2.3.
    Note: artwork removed to flat box # 3.1
    - College years, 1948-1952: correspondence, admissions statement, test scores, report cards, papers, programs, clippings, gay bar ephemera, 1.11.
    - College years, Bob Curiel, 1951-1952: one love letter to Curiel and lyrics to song Curiel played on guitar, 1.12.
    - College years, design, 1950-1952: sketches, notes, 1.13.
    - College years, classics course, 1951: notes and papers for classical civilizations course, 1.14.
    - College years, private notes, 1950-1951: reading and thinking notes, quotes, notes, clippings on homosexuality, 2.1.
    - College years, psychological analyses, 1951-1952: analyses of himself and others, 2.2.
    - College years, writing, 1950-1952: poetry fragments, translations, beginning of a story, 2.3.
    - College years, artwork, 1951-1952: Rosenthal's drawings and sketches, mostly charcoal on newsprint., Flat Box 3.1.
  - Cuba, 2.4-2.11
    - Cuba, 1960-1962: letters, clippings, typescripts, photograph, 2.4.
    - Cuba, The Debriefing, 1961: typescript by Rosenthal, 2.5.
    - Cuba, The PM Affair, 1961: typescript by Rosenthal, 2.6.
    - Cuba, Jose Marti, ca. 1961: photographs of Marti and his exhumation, pamphlet, Vindicacion de Cuba, 2.7.
    - Cuba, Bay of Pigs, 1961: photographs of invasion, 2.8.
    - Cuba, Havana, 1961: photographs by Rosenthal, 2.9.
    - Cuba, literary figures, 1960-1961: photographs of Pablo Neruda et al.; also meeting of artists and writers, including Rosenthal., 2.10.
    - Cuba, Tumba Francesa, 1961: photographs of Cuban film, 2.11.
  - Declaration of Conscience Committee, 1961: letters by Philip Whalen, LeRoi Jones, et al.; also telegram, postcards, newsletter., 2.12.
  - Dissertation correspondence and criticism, 1958: letters, dissertation proposal, 2.13.
  - Hare Krishna, 1967-1968: correspondence; includes ephemera, postcards, and photograph., 2.14.
  - Healthcare in New York, 1959-1967: bills, receipts, identification cards, letters, 2.15.
  - Illinois Institute of Technology, 1954: letters, notes, drawing, report card, 2.16.
  - Job hunting, 1959-1962: letters, business cards, notes, 2.17.
  - Navy correspondence course evaluation project, 1952-1954: letters, notes, telegrams, 4.1
  - New York City community college, 1965-1967: letter, student papers, notes, notebooks, 4.2.
  - New York City notes and documents, 1964-1967: address book, notebook, identification cards, draft of poem on envelope, 4.3.
  - Oahu, Hawaii, 1957: transcribed postcards, 4.4.
  - Programmed instruction, 1962: letters, notes, 4.5.
  - Salaries and taxes, 1948-1968: check stubs, tax forms, etc., 4.6.
  - Selective Service, 1950-1952: letters and forms, 4.7.
  - Tangier, Morocco, 1962-1964: letters, notes, business card, photographs of Paul Bowles, Peter Birnbaum, Ira Cohen, Rosenthal, et al., 4.8
  - Teaching, Chicago, 1955-1957: notes, Rosenthal's transcripts, teaching materials, letters, 4.9.
  - Teaching, New York, 1962-1965: forms, notes, letters, teaching materials, 4.10.
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1966: letters, clipping, 4.11.
  - University of Chicago, 1952-1958: letters, forms, transcripts, identification card, audograph disc, 4.12.
  - University of Chicago, Counseling Center, 1934-1954: letters, forms, and notes from Rosenthal's work as a counselor., 40.1.
    Note: closed for privacy until 2014.
- Series II. CORRESPONDENCE
  This series contains incoming and outgoing correspondence. Rosenthal often made carbon copies of his outgoing correspondence, so many files in this series offer insight into the development of his personal and professional relationships with a number of prominent Beat figures, including Allen Ginsberg, Herbert Huncke, and William Burroughs. As an editor, much of Rosenthal's correspondence included the exchange of manuscripts and other materials. Rather than removing these items and placing them in a separate series, we have left all items with the correspondence files in order to preserve the original context of these materials. Accordingly, in addition to correspondence, this series contains a large number of manuscripts and typescripts, as well as artwork, photographs, booklets, periodicals, and ephemera.
  - Alexander, Dorris, 1951-1952: extensive correspondence; includes artwork, clipping, invitation, and postcard., 5.1.
  - Allan, Richard, 1952-1954: letters, greeting card, 5.2.
  - Allen, Donald, 1958-2000: correspondence, postcard, 5.3.
  - Ansen, Alan, 1958-1964: correspondence; includes typescript of "Running" and review of Gregory Corso's "Gasoline.", 5.4.
  - Aronowitz, Al, 1959-1997: correspondence; includes The Blacklisted Journalist (1997)., 5.5.
  - Arrabal, Fernando, 1959-1960: letter, flyers, photographs, 5.6.
  - Bassin, Barry, 1966-1968: extensive correspondence; includes clippings, magazine, Night, issues 1 and 2, (1968), porno press and Hare Krishna press fragments., 5.7.
  - Bathhurst, Bill, 1966-1967: correspondence; includes typescript of poem, "HE.", 5.8.
  - Beckett, Samuel, 1958: letter, 5.9.
  - Benfield, Michael, 1966-1969: correspondence; includes copy of hospital admittance form and manuscript of poem, "Freedom Lost" written on a paper towel., 5.10.
  - Bentzel, Joseph, 1968-1969: correspondence; includes photographs., 5.11.
  - Birnbaum, Peter, 1964-1974: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, notebooks, photographs, artwork, and business cards., 5.12.
  - Birnbaum, Peter, ca. 1964-1974: printing scraps, clippings, artwork, 5.13.
  - Birnbaum, Peter, 1968: Marbels from Cockaroch Morseleum by Isser Aronvici, published by Birnbaum., 5.14.
  - Bowles, Paul, 1959-1978: extensive correspondence regarding life in Tangier, Morocco and Big Table submissions and publications; includes two photographs (one landscape, one of Bowles) and typescripts, "Ketama-taza" (1959) and "The Ball at Sidi Hosni" (ca. 1960)., 5.15.
  - Boyd, Robert, 1960-1961: note, typescripts of poems, 5.16.
  - Brand, Arlene, 1957-1961: correspondence; includes greeting card and Audograph FL-60 disc., 5.17.
  - Breen, Walter, 1960: postcard, 5.18.
  - Bremser, Ray and Bonnie, 1958-1962: extensive correspondence; includes letter from Ray Bremser to Gregory Corso; also photographs, postcards, artwork, manuscripts, and typescripts., 5.19.
  - Bremser, Ray, ca. 1959: typescript of "The Square", 5.20.
  - Brenan, Gerald, 1964: letter, 5.21.
  - Brown, Chris, 1965-1968: correspondence, postcard, 5.22.
  - Brown, Geoffrey, 1966-1967: extensive correspondence; includes typescripts and photographs., 5.23.
  - Brown, Geoffrey, 1967-1987: correspondence; includes typescripts and "A Free Book (But not without Cost)," a binder of poetry (1984), inscribed to Rosenthal., 5.24.
  - Burroughs, William, 1958-1962, 6.1-6.7.
    See also Big Table, folder # 33.4, for Naked Lunch typescripts
    - Burroughs, 1958-1959: extensive correspondence, including correspondence between Burroughs, Rosenthal, Allen Ginsberg, et al., regarding the publication of Naked Lunch in The Chicago Review and Big Table and by Olympia and Grove Press; includes typescript portions of Naked Lunch, some with edits by Allen Ginsberg and Rosenthal; proofs for The Chicago Review; also publication offers, legal papers, and Burroughs's artwork., 6.1.
    - Burroughs, 1959-1961: extensive correspondence, including Burroughs, Rosenthal, Allen Ginsberg, et al.; includes Rosenthal's notes on editing Naked Lunch submitted to Grove Press; also typescripts, telegram, publication offers, clippings, proofs, contract, Burroughs's artwork, and notices of seizure for Naked Lunch and The Soft Machine., 6.2.
    - Burroughs, loose typescripts, 1958-1960: portions of Naked Lunch, including "The Hospital," "Soul Crackers," and "The Examination," some with edits by Burroughs and Rosenthal (ca. 1958); also fragment with edits by Gregory Corso and "Conspiracy" title page (dropped from Naked Lunch "Hospital" section) with edits by Allen Ginsberg., 6.3.
    - Burroughs, typescript, 1959: "Queer" from Naked Lunch with edits by Burroughs and Allen Ginsberg; also biographical notes., 6.4.
    - Burroughs, typescript, 1959: "In Search of Yage" from Naked Lunch with edits by Burroughs and Allen Ginsberg., 6.5.
    - Burroughs, The Naked Lunch, 1959: published by Olympia Press; first copy to enter US; contains Rosenthal's edits throughout; used by Burroughs as base manuscript for Grove edition., 6.6.
    - Burroughs, My Own Mag, 1960: zine with drawing of Burroughs on the cover; pages 3-4 edited by Burroughs., 6.7.
  - Cabrera Infante, Guillermo, 1961: letters, 6.8.
  - Cabrera Infante, Guillermo, 1961: photographs removed from folder # 6.8, 6.9.
  - Capote, Truman, 1958-1959: letters, telegram, postcards, 6.10.
  - Carroll, Paul, 1957-1959: extensive correspondence; includes notes, clipping, telegrams., 7.1.
  - Carroll, Paul, 1959: extensive correspondence; includes telegrams., 7.2.
  - Carroll, Paul, 1960-1988: correspondence; includes notes, telegrams, postcards, clipping., 7.3.
  - Casey, Calvert, 1961: letter, 7.4.
  - Chester, Alfred, 1964: letters, note, 7.5.
  - Ciardi, John, 1959: letters, galley proof, clipping, 7.6.
  - Clay, Mel, 1964: correspondence; includes typescript of poem., 7.7.
  - Cohen, Ira, 1963-1989: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, prints., 7.8.
  - Cohen, Ira, Nexus, 1998: vol. 33, no. 2, dedication to Rosenthal in 2001., 7.9.
  - Conner, Bruce, ca. 1960: correspondence; includes mail art, brochures, exhibition announcements, catalogs, clippings, and artwork., 7.10.
  - Corso, Gregory, 1958-2001: correspondence; includes typescripts of a review of Doctor Sax by Jack Kerouac and of "On Chessman's Crime" (1960); also postcards, clippings, two obituaries and tributes to Corso in Poetry Flash (2001)., 7.11.
    See also Big Table, folder # 33.4, for Corso typescripts
  - Corso, Gregory, 1959: six photographs of 1959 poetry reading; the photographs picture Corso, Jack Kerouac, Ray and Bonnie Bremser, et al.; removed from folder # 7.11., 7.12.
  - Coulter, Michael, ca. 1966-1967: extensive correspondence; includes business card, photographs, and artwork, felt-tip sketches and drawings for Pole Vault by Edward Marshall., 7.13.
  - Cowen, Elise, 1956-1962: correspondence; includes identification card, etc., 7.14.
  - Cowen, Elise, slides, no date: slides removed from folder # 7.14, 7.15.
  - Creeley, Robert, 1958: letter to Creeley, 7.16.
  - Cummings, David, 1959: letters, notes, postcard, 7.17.
  - Curiel, Robert, 1951-1989: correspondence, 7.18.
  - Curley, A., 1957-1958: correspondence; includes notes and cards., 7.19.
  - Dahlberg, Edward, 1958-1977: extensive correspondence; includes clippings, postcards, and typescripts: "Tears of the Virgin" (ca. 1959); "Because I was Flesh," (one page and scrap with Rosenthal's edits); Dahlberg's biography., 7.20.
    See also Big Table, folder # 33.4, for Dahlberg typescripts
  - Dahlberg, Edward, Sewanee Review, 1959: no. 2, inscribed to Rosenthal, 8.1.
  - Dahlberg, Edward, TriQuarterly, 1970: no. 19; issue dedicated to Dahlberg., 8.2.
  - Dahlberg, Julia, 1965-1993: correspondence; includes postcards, greeting cards, business cards, legal papers, and photographs., 8.3.
  - Dahlberg, R'Lene, 1959-1982: correspondence; includes postcards and galley proof of Allen Ginsberg's introduction to Leave the Word Alone by Ed Marshall., 8.4.
  - Deemer, Bill, 1968: letters, postcard, 8.5.
  - DeFanti, Charles, 1972-1974: correspondence, 8.6.
  - Di Prima, Diane, 1960-1969: letter to Allen Ginsberg, greeting card, typescript, "Thinks on Westernness", 8.7.
  - Dorfman, Elsa, 1960-2000: correspondence; includes drafts of statements about poetry by nine poets for the Paterson Society; also postcards of Dorfman's photographs and photocopied articles from Views: The Journal of Photography in New England (1981)., 8.8.
  - Dowden, George, 1960-1966: letters, 8.9.
  - Dragudze, Tamara, 1963-1965: letters, 8.10.
  - Edelstein, Richard, 1951-1954: extensive correspondence, 8.11.
  - Elkin, Gay, 1949-1952: correspondence; includes greeting cards and a reprint of "Transvestism: An Empirical Study" by Louise Lawrence, from International Journal of Sexology (1951)., 8.12.
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1958-1964: correspondence, including letters regarding the suppression of the 1959 winter issue of The Chicago Review; also City Lights Books postcards., 8.13.
  - Fisher, Melvin, 1967: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence with Rosenthal, Geoffrey Brown, the Fisher Family, et al.; includes manuscripts, and artwork, 8.14.
  - Fisher, Melvin, 1967-1976: extensive correspondence, 8.15.
  - Fisher, Melvin, ca. 1967-1968: photographs removed from folders # 8.14-8.15 of Melvin Fisher, Geoffrey Brown, et al.; photostrips of Melvin Fisher, Rosenthal, et al., 8.16.
  - Fles, John, 1958-1962: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, telegram, The Trembling Lamb (1960), edited by John Fles; also includes typescript of "The Remembers," a story about Ray and Bonnie Bremser, and typescript of "The Boom" (1962)., 9.1.
  - Forbes, Sumner, 1962: note, letter, 9.2.
  - Ford, Charles Henri, View, 1945: Series 5, No. 1, 9.3.
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1965-1984: correspondence; includes posters, artwork, and postcards., 9.4.
  - Foster, Pat, 1948: card, clipping, 9.5.
  - Fusco, Peter, 1966-1967: photostrip of Rosenthal and Peter Fusco, note, letter, manuscript, "O Perverted Generation", 9.6.
  - Ginsberg, Allen, 1949-1999, 9.7-9.13.
    Note: oversized periodical removed to flat box # 3.2.
    - Ginsberg, 1949-1959: typescript "Patterson" (ca. 1949); extensive correspondence; includes correspondence regarding William Burroughs, Gregory Corso, Gary Snyder, Jack Kerouac, Robert Creeley, Alan Ansen, et al.; correspondence regarding the suppression of the 1959 winter issue of The Chicago Review and Rosenthal's resignation; Jargon 31: 14 Poets, 1 Artist (1958)., 9.7.
    - Ginsberg, 1959-1965: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence regarding Big Table, Ginsberg's travels in India, and Rosenthal's stay in Tangier, Morocco; also includes Ginsberg's feedback on Sheeper; typescript of poem, "Kali Ma" (ca. 1963)., 9.8.
    - Ginsberg, 1966-1971: extensive correspondence; includes correspondence regarding Herbert Huncke, Don Allen, Jack Smith, et al.; clipped articles about Ginsberg; Village Voice, "Hustler for Life" (1966); Life, "The Guru Comes to Kansas" (1966); transcription of taped recording; includes discussion between Rosenthal and Ginsberg about the 1967 Arab-Israeli War., 9.9.
    - Ginsberg, photographs, 1962-1971: photographs of Ginsberg's travels in India sent to Marc Schleifer with captions on back (1962); mounted photograph, Allen Ginsberg singing at the Blue Angel Cabaret in San Francisco (1971); removed from folders # 9.8-9.9., 9.10.
    - Ginsberg, 1971: typescripts for "Interrogation of a Businessman by the Interior Police" (interview of Ginsberg by Rosenthal)., 9.11.
    - Ginsberg, 1973-1992: extensive correspondence; includes letters in defense of Abbie Hoffman; posters; Little Free Press pamphlets; memorandum of a North Beach conversation between Rosenthal, Ginsberg, and Serge Grenier (1981); programs for poetry readings; clipping; copy of Rosenthal's inscription in Ginsberg's copy of Sheeper., 9.12.
    - Ginsberg, 1994-1999: correspondence; clippings; exhibit announcements; ICA newsletter; Rosenthal's notes from last visit with Ginsberg., 9.13.
    - Ginsberg, Village Voice, 1997: vol. 42, no. 15; includes memorial feature, "Remembering Allen Ginsberg.", 3.2.
    - Ginsberg, Allen Ginsberg Reads Kaddish, 1966: LP record, inscribed by Ginsberg to Rosenthal, 41.
  - Gitana, Nina, 1960: greeting card, letters, 10.1.
  - Goodman, Paul, 1960: typescript, "The Fate of Dr. Reich's Books (The Injunction against Reich's Books)," appeared in Kulcher 2 (1960)., 10.2.
  - Grady, Panna, 1966-1968: correspondence; includes greeting cards., 10.3.
  - Gurin, David, 1961-1968: extensive correspondence; includes notes, postcards, and four typescripts by "A. Burgereau"; also Gurin's comments on Sheeper., 10.4.
  - Gurin, David, 1968-1999: extensive correspondence; includes postcards, clippings, and greeting cards., 10.5.
  - Gurin, David, 1959-1999: photographs of David Gurin and others removed from folders # 10.4-10.5., 10.6.
  - Haber, Daniel, ca. 1967-1980: correspondence; includes artwork, postcards, and photograph., 10.7.
  - Hall, Tevelda, 1955-1959: correspondence; includes flyer., 10.8.
  - Hamburger, Michael, 1958: letters, 10.9.
  - Harris Family, 1968-1989: photographs of Harris family, flyers, 10.10.
  - Harris, George III, 1967-1979: extensive correspondence between Harris, Rosenthal, et al.; includes clippings, postcards, greeting card, photographs., 10.11.
  - Harris, George III, 1980-1986: extensive correspondence between Harris, Rosenthal, et al.; includes postcards, notes, clipping, Ultra High Hollywood News (four issues, 1980), photograph., 10.12.
  - Harvey, Arthur, 1961-1968: postcard, booklet, Theory and Practice of Civil Disobedience, 10.13.
  - Hasselwood, Dave, 1959-1981: extensive correspondence; includes artwork, flyer, photographs, and typescript "The Current Fall of the Social World.", 10.14.
  - Heine, William, 1961-1974: extensive correspondence; includes artwork, mostly pencil drawings on index cards., 11.1.
  - Heine, William, 1961-1966: ink drawing and collage (3 folders), 11.2-11.4.
  - Heine, William, 1966: three-part acetate overlays for use in Polevault (2 folders), 11.5-11.6.
  - Heine, William, 1973: cover designs for Polevault, 11.7.
  - Heine, William, 1961: tie-dye wall hangings, 11.8.
  - Heuga, Robert, 1960: correspondence; includes postcards., 12.1.
  - Horwitz, Charles, 1960-1962: correspondence, 12.2.
  - Howard, Richard, 1958: correspondence, 12.3.
  - Hudson, Robert, 1960: correspondence; includes greeting card., 12.4.
  - Huncke, Herbert, 1959-1973, 12.5-16.4.